ibtimes.co.uk 2018-02-07

# International Business Times UK ::: Privacy & Policy

This policy was last updated on March 7, 2016

 **Our Commitment to your Privacy**

This is the privacy policy for IBTIMES.com and other IBTIMES websites and mobile applications, which describes how we collect, store and use non-sensitive personal data. IBTIMES comprises of the IBTIMES.com website, IBTIMES iPhone and Android apps, the IBTIMES publications, and IBTIMES Limited, as well as IBT Media Limited. This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to in it) describes how we process any personal data which you provide us with or which we collect from you. Please read our policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

By visiting IBTIMES.co.uk, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy. We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy, and do our best to ensure that your data is protected. We do not intentionally collect any information on children under the age of 14. If you are a parent or guardian and notify us that details of children under 14 years of age have been obtained, we will ensure that these details are deleted.

 **Information we collect about you.**

When you visit our website we may automatically take the following non personal information:

  * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform;
  * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

A full list of first party cookies are listed in a table below

 **Information we receive from other sources.**

We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites or mobile apps and services we provide. In this case we will have informed you when we collected that data that it may be shared internally and combined with data collected on this site. We also work closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

The information we may collect can either be data that identifies you (eg. your name, address or email) as well as information that does not, but which may help us to improve our services, for example by evaluating behaviour patterns when users visit our website or apps. This can either be given implicitly to us by you (in forms), or anonymised non personal information collected by us about you. Some examples of this includes the information you give us when you email us or register to use or fill in other forms on IBTIMES.co.uk, subscribe to IBTIMES’s products and services, post comments or participate in the IBTIMES community, submit corrections, enter a competition or promotion, download IBTIMES mobile apps or digital issues and when you report a problem with our site. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information, personal description and photograph.

 **How we use your information**

We use information held about you in the following ways:  

  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
  * to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
  * to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you. If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on any registration form on which we collect your data;
  * to notify you about changes to our service;
  * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * to improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;
  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about goods or services that may interest you or them.
  * Information we receive from other sources. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

**A full list of first party cookies are listed in a table below**

 **How we may use your information**

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006. We may share your information with carefully selected third parties including:

 **Affiliates:**   
We may share your information with companies that are affiliated with IBTIMES and its related companies.

 **Social Network and Interactive Tools:**  
Certain features on our websites give you an opportunity to interact with us and others. These may include forums, message boards, chats, submitting a letter to the editor, creating community profiles, and rating, tagging and commenting on articles. When you use these features you should be aware that any information you submit, including your name, location and e-mail address, may be publicly available to others. We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit through these interactive features.

 **Corporate, Third-Party, and Student Subscriptions:**  
If your subscription is provided in whole or in part by your employer or other third party, we may notify the provider when you access or use your subscription. If you have a student subscription associated with a school, college or university or school, we may notify them to confirm your subscription, access or use. When providing these notices, we may reveal limited amounts of your information such as your name or email address. Service Providers and Agents: We might share your information with commercial partners that provide services to help our websites and apps work, including delivering subscriptions, serving, customizing or delivering marketing or adverts that are relevant to your interests, and auditing. We will not allow these companies to use your information for any other purpose.

 **Special Circumstances:**  
Sometimes, we do have to disclose your data without providing with a choice in order to protect our company’s legal rights or those of our employees, agents and contractors, or other companies related to us. This may be, for example, if we feel it necessary to protect the safety and security of visitors to our websites and apps; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with the law. If any of our group companies are sold to a third party, your information, we may transfer your information to a third party as part of that transaction.

 **Third Party Promotional Offers:**  
If you subscribe to our print publications, we may share your contact information with other companies whose products and services may be of interest to you. While many of our subscribers appreciate receiving offerings from these companies, if you prefer that we do not share your information for this purpose, please contact our ‘data controller’ using the details supplied below.

 **Analytics and search engine providers** that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.

 **We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:**

To enable subscription payments, we work with reputable third party service providers that collect and store billing and credit card information including Chase Paymentech and Piano Media in Slovakia. This information is used by the third parties to perform billing and for their internal business purposes. Examples of these uses include fulfilling orders and processing credit card payments. Your personal information passed through Piano Media is governed its privacy policy there. Your information is not shared by these parties with other third parties and is not used for marketing third party products.

If you want to opt out of receiving marketing from us, any of our affiliated companies or any of our promotional partners, or if you want to update your preferences, you will need to contact each of our publications separately, as indicated below: International Business Times Online and any other IBT Media properties: To opt out of receiving marketing from International Business Times Online, if you are a subscriber visit our Member Centre. Others may notify us by contacting Customer Service at info@IBTIMES.co.uk. IBTIMES: Subscribers to IBTIMES may contact Customer Service at info@IBTIMES.co.uk

If you are a current subscriber of any of our publications, please remember to include your account number and phone number in the body of your e-mail or letter, and if you choose to opt-out via e-mail, please include "Opt-out" in the subject line. Please note that we may still disclose your opt-out information to third parties, to ensure that you do not receive any future notifications from them, in accordance with applicable laws.

 **Where we store your personal data**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"), in order to use it as listed in **How we may use your Information**. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet can never be 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. We will retain your data for as long as necessary to permit us to use it in the ways such as those described above.

 **Cookies**

Cookie Name| Type| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics| Analytics tracking Cookie - 1st party| Provides market research data to website owners through a mixture of online surveys and the use of web beacons. It only collects non personal information|  You can read more about the privacy policy here - <http://www.comscore.com/About-comScore/Privacy-Policy> To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
ScoreCard Research Beacon - Comscore| Analytics Cookie - 1st party| Tracks website content and anonymised user data.|  You can read more about the privacy policy here - <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en> To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <https://www.scorecardresearch.com/Preferences.aspx>  
NetRatings SiteCensus| Analytics Cookie - 1st party| This Site also uses Nielsen//NetRating's SiteCensus service to collect statistical site usage information from your web browser and through the use of cookies and its Market Intelligence service to administer random "pop-up" surveys while visiting the Site.| For more information on the information that NetRatings collects and processes through these services, please read their [Cookie and Privacy Policy. ](http://www.nielsen-netratings.com/corp.jsp)  
Forensiq| Analytics Cookie - 1st party| Helps eliminate impression fraud, click fraud, affiliate fraud and cookie stuffing. They do not use any data collected for behavioral, re-targeting or other interest-based advertising.| You can read more about the privacy policy here - <https://forensiq.com/privacy-policy/#service-privacy>  
Facebook Social graph - 1st and 3rd Party| Behavioural tracking cookie| If a person has visited Facebook and visits a website with a social plugin, the browser sends us information in order to load Facebook content on that page. The data we receive may include info like the person's user ID, the website they're visiting, the date and time, and other browser-related info. We record some of this info and may use it to improve our products and services and to show people more interesting and useful ads.| You can learn about opting out of ads based on your activity here <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>  
Chartbeat| Analytics Cookie - 1st party| Tracks what stories users are most interested in and ones that are trending. More information can be found here - <https://chartbeat.com/privacy/>| Chartbeat uses two cookies. One cookie (_chartbeat2) is used to register whether a user has visited the Customer Website before (to calculate “new vs returning” users). The other (_SUPERFLY_nosample) is used only if a Customer exceeds its plan’s traffic limit. When the traffic limit is reached the cookie is set and will disable the beacon from that Customer for one hour. The chartbeat2 cookie will remain valid as to any given website visitor or user, until the user elects to disable it. The _SUPERFLY_nosample cookie is valid for one hour.  
Visual Web Optimiser (VWO)| A/B testing tool - 1st party| Tracks which pages or content works the best using A/B and MVT testing tools| View VWO privacy policy here - <https://vwo.com/privacy-policy/> To opt out go to <https://vwo.com/opt-out/>  
BlueKai (Oracle)| Behavioural tracking Cookie - 1st party| BlueKai collects anonymised data about a users web usage to build a anonymous profile of who and what they are interested in. Full details can be read here - [http://www.bluekai.com/consumers.php ](http://www.bluekai.com/consumers.php)|  You can review the data that Bluekai has colllected about your computer and webbrowser here: <http://www.bluekai.com/registry/>  
Nativo| Native Advertising Cookie - 1st party| Full details can be read here - <https://www.nativo.net/#privacy-policy>|   
GetClicky| Analytics Cookie - 1st party| Tracks what stories users are most interested in and ones that are trending. No personal information is collected. Full details can be read here - <https://clicky.com/terms#privacy>|   
Grapeshot| Contextual targetting Cookie - 1st party| Grapeshot supplies a contextual targeting platform that uses the keywords it finds in web pages. it does nto collect personal information. Full details can be read here - <https://www.grapeshot.com/privacy/>|   
Quantcast| Behavioural analytics tracking Cookie - 1st party| Quantcast collects anonymised data to understand the characteristics and demographics of the people who visit the website. Full details can be read here - <https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/>|  To opt out of Quantcast collecting data - <https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out>  
Taboola| Cookie - 1st party| Taboola collect User Information automatically through a User’s use of or interaction with our Services. They automatically collect Information through a User’s use of our Services through cookies and other technologies, like most other web-based services. This Information may include, without limitation, information about a User’s operating system, the webpages accessed by Users within our Customers’ websites, the link that led a User to a Customers' website, the dates and times a User accesses a Customers' website, event information (e.g., system crashes), and general location information (e.g., city and state). They also collect User IP addresses but partially mask the collected IP address.|  You can review the data that Taboola has colllected about your computer and web browser here: <https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy> and opt out here <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>  
Moat| Analytics Ad Cookie - 1st party|  Collects limited personal data (if knowingly shared) and non-personally identifiable information (“NPI”) to identify computers or mobile device that they have previously interacted with.|  Full details can be read here - <http://www.moat.com/privacy>. You can opt out of being tracked here - <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>  
SkimLinks| Affiliate cookie - 1st party| Creates affiliate links from external links to track a purchase/ click through. Only NPI data is collected| Full details can be read here - <http://skimlinks.com/privacy-policy> . You can opt out of NPI data being collected here <http://optout.skimlinks.com/?tested=1>  
Amazon Associates| Affiliate cookie - 1st party| Tracks where user came from before clicking on Amazon product link|   
Adsense (Google)| Ad cookie - 1st party| You can review the types of cookies and data DoublecClick collects here - <https://www.google.co.uk/policies/technologies/types/>| If you want to opt-out from having CPX cookies on your browser collecting NPI you may go to <https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated?hl=en>  
Captify| 1st party cookie| The information you will provide to us are keyword data relating to the search which has led users to your site or carried out on your site, and (ii) technical data relating to those users’ devices, i.e.:The referral search term (i.e., the term entered into a search engine which displayed your site as a search result); The onsite search term (i.e., the term entered in the search box on your site); The type of browser used by the user; The operating system of the user’s device; Time and date of landing on the site or performing the onsite search; Referring Site URL; Client IP| Users may prevent Captify cookies from being set on their devices at <http://www.captify.co.uk/privacy.php>. That further information relating to online advertising and ways to control cookies is available at <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/>  
  
A lot of the advertisements you see on the IBTtimes are provided by other organisations. Some of these organisations use their own anonymous cookies to track how many people have seen a particular ad, or to track how many people have seen it more than once. The companies that generate these cookies have their own privacy policies, and we have no access to read or write these cookies. These organizations may use their cookies to anonymously target advertising to you on other websites, based on your visit to the IBTimes. You can opt out of many of these cooklies by going here **<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>**

All modern browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings will typically be found in the 'options' or 'preferences' menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the 'Help' option in your browser for more details.

We do not recommend turning cookies off when visiting any IBT Media websites, as this will prevent you from signing in, and using many of the services on the site.

You have the right to choose whether or not to accept cookies and to set your own cookie preferences on your computer. These preferences can be to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. However, by opting not to receive cookies at any time, certain features of the Site and Shop cannot be provided and so accordingly you may not be able to enjoy the Site and Shop to their fullest. All web browsers are different and to learn how to change your cookie preferences, check the "Help" menu of your browser.

For further information about cookies and how to control their use, please visit the following third party educational resources:[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

 **Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

Your legal rights, and how to contact IBTIMES about your data

We are required by the UK Data Protection Act 1998 to provide you with the contact details for our “data controller”. You should contact our data controller if you have any questions, comments or requests regarding this privacy policy. The data controller is IBTIMES Limited of 25 Canada Square, Canary Wharf, London E14 5LQ or info@IBTIMES.co.uk. You have the right to ask us NOT to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to do use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at info@IBTIMES.co.uk

You also have the right to access personal information held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please email us at info@IBTIMES.co.uk. There will be an administrative charge of £10, which helps us to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.
